Rizki Perdana Bowo Laksono

Yogyakarta, 55242 | +62 896 0136 1061 | perdana.rizki16@gmail.com

About Me

I've been working as a backend engineer for 4 years and like to work on implementing business ideas and system concepts into a full-fledged API. I enjoy generating new ideas and devising feasible solutions to broadly relevant problems.

Competence & Skill

- Backend (Ruby, Node JS, PHP, Python)
- Database (Postgresql, Mysql, MongoDB)
- Frontend (React JS, Vue JS, Jquery)
- Rest Framework (Grape, Swagger)

Work Experience

PT. Lentera Bangsa Benderang / Binar Academy (Jakarta, Indonesia)

Backend Engineer (August 2021 - Current)

- Utilizing Ruby On Rails to implement working API functions for mobile, website, and services.
- Creating unit tests using Rspec.
- Working with databases and ORM.
- Developing using Linux environment, Git, and Docker to keep application consistency and maintainability.

PT. Gamatechno Indonesia (Yogyakarta, Indonesia)

Backend Engineer Products (December 2020 - July 2021)

- Build REST API using PHP Lumen and Codeigniter.
- Working with unit tests.
- Building full stack applications using Javascript stack (Node JS, Express JS, and Vue JS).

Quality Assurance (February 2020 - December 2020)

- Responsibility to testing applications on mobile, desktop, and website.
- Doing API Testing using Postman.
- Doing functional tests through positive tests and negative testing.
- Creating documentation for UAT.

PT. Diginet Media (Yogyakarta, Indonesia)

Backend Engineer (September 2014 - January 2016)

- Developing websites using PHP frameworks such as Codeigniter, Laravel, and Yii.
- Utilizing MySql and Postgresql as primary databases.
- Developing clean and functional code using microservice.

Education

Yogyakarta State University (2016-2020)

Bachelor Degree

- Developing Roomania app (room booking app) as contestant app for CPPBT (*Calon Perusahaan Pemula Berbasis Teknologi/ Prospective Technology-Based Startup Company*) in 2018.
- Becoming IT Leader Division on KSPM (Komunitas Studi Pasar Modal/Capital Market Study Community)

Notable Project

Binaracademy API (Sep 2021 - current)

Backend Engineer (Ruby on Rails)

- Building service API using Ruby on Rails and available to be consumed by web service and mobile clients.
- Using a test-first development method and making sure we cover corner cases.
- Using GIT as software versioning and CI/CD for better agile methodology implementation.

Cared (Dec 2020 - Aug 2021)

Backend Engineer (Node JS)

- Building a full stack healthcare app using javascript stack.
- Maintaining code consistency and functionalities using Mocha and Linters.
- Mainly using Gitlab for repository and CI/CD.
- Using Postgresql as Database and Express JS stack with ORM as model controller.

Yogyakarta Government One Gate Service System (July 2014 - Jan 2016)

Backend Engineer (PHP)

- Making full stack applications for local government utilizing Codeigniter as MVC.
- Using bootstrap and Jquery as frontend main framework.
- Working on MySql as the main database.